Okay, so in this video, we're going to
discuss the requirements management plan.
And the requirements management plan,
just like any of the other subsidiary
plans, it is a component of the project
management plan.
And again, just like any other subsidiary
plan, it's documenting procedures,
it's documenting how, how we're going to
collect requirements, how we're going to
plan, manage, execute, monitor and control,
the requirements management process.
It does not contain the actual
requirements itself.
So first of all, though, we really should
discuss exactly what is a requirement.
What is a requirement?
So a requirement is what we are going to
deliver.
And refers to the what, what we are going
to deliver.
Not how are we going to deliver it.
It's what we are going to deliver.
That is a requirement.
What the customer wants, what the customer
needs, right?
the agreed upon capability, a condition of
the product, service, or result.
I mean, that's the official definition.
You don't need to
memorize the definition, but
that basically is the
definition of a requirement.
And really it is what we are going to
deliver, what the customer wants,
what the customer needs, and so and so
forth.
Now, there are many, many types of
requirements as well.
Right, so we're going to cover that in a
separate video.
We'll talk about that in a separate video.
But just as a high-level summary,
right, you've got requirements related to
the product, requirements
are related to the
stakeholder, what the
stakeholder requirements.
You've got something
called solution requirements,
non-functional requirements,
and so and so forth.
There are many, many types of
requirements, right?
So, but a requirement basically is what we
are going to deliver.
Now, the requirements management plan is
going to be documenting procedures.
First of all, it's going to document what
kind of requirements we need.
Right.
As I mentioned, there's many, many types
of requirements.
So what kind of requirements do we need?
But in addition, it's going to be
documenting how.
It's going to be documenting procedures.
So how are we going to plan, manage,
execute the collection of requirements,
monitor and control the requirements?
How are we going to do that?
What are the procedures for that?
Who are we collecting requirements from?
what level of details do these
requirements need to be collected in right
what level of details do we need again
remember progressive elaboration right
we're starting off at something high level
we're going to drill down into the details
right we may collect high level
requirements then we may start drilling
down to more the detail requirements right
from those high level then we will collect
we will then you know figure out some more
of the details of those requirements right
so there may be more than one step right
so we may need to reach out to the same
stakeholder several times to get a good
detailed set requirements.
So what level of detail do we need to
collect our requirements in?
Where are we going to be documenting our
requirements?
So the requirements management plan is
documenting all of these procedures.
How will be collected, where it's going to
be collected, who is collected from,
where it's documented, what
happens if halfway through
the project we realized
we've missed a requirement?
What do we do in that situation?
How do we handle that situation?
What happens if halfway
through the project,
the customer wants some
additional requirements?
How do we handle that situation?
Again, all of that is documented in the
Requirements Management Plan.
So the Requirements Management Plan,
again, are documenting procedures.
They're documenting the how.
They do not contain any of their
requirements itself.
The requirements are going to be
documented in the requirements document,
but the management plan is always
documenting how.
It's always documenting procedures.